So, let us go back to our neural network with our weights and our input.
それでは 重みと入力を適用したニューラルネットワークに戻りましょう
And recall that the weights with superscript 1 belong to the first layer,
重み上付き1は第1層に 重み上付き2は第2層に属することを
and the weights with superscript 2 belong to the second layer.
思い出してください
Also, recall that the bias is not called b anymore.
また バイアスをbと呼ばなくなったことも思い出してください
Now, it is called W31,
ここでは W31 W32 などと呼びます
W32 etc. for convenience,
便宜上です
so that we can have everything in matrix notation.
これで 行列表記にすることができます
And now what happens with the input?
入力はどうなっているでしょうか?
So, let us do the feedforward process.
フィードフォワードプロセスを実行してみましょう
In the first layer,
第1層では 入力を受け取り
we take the input and multiply it by the weights and that gives us h1,
それに重みを乗算すると h1を求められます
which is a linear function of the input and the weights.
これは入力と重みの線形関数です
Same thing with h2,
h2も同様で
given by this formula over here.
この式で求められます
Now, in the second layer,
第2層では h1とh2
we would take this h1 and h2 and the new bias,
および新しいバイアスにシグモイド関数を適用します
apply the sigmoid function,
さらに線形関数を適用するため
and then apply a linear function to them by multiplying them by
各値に重みを乗算して
the weights and adding them to get a value of h. And finally,
すべてを加算し hの値を求めます
in the third layer,
最後に第3層で
we just take a sigmoid function of h to get
hのシグモイド関数を使って予測
our prediction or probability between 0 and 1, which is ŷ.
つまり0～1の確率を求めます  これがŷです
And we can read this in more condensed notation by saying that
これをより簡潔に表記するために
the matrix corresponding to the first layer is W superscript 1,
第1層に対応する行列をW1
the matrix corresponding to the second layer is W superscript 2,
第2層に対応する行列をW2とします
and then the prediction we had is just going to be
W2のシグモイドをW1のシグモイドと組み合わせて
the sigmoid of W superscript 2 combined with
入力xに適用したものが予測となります
the sigmoid of W superscript 1 applied to the input x and that is feedforward.
これがフィードフォワードです
Now, we are going to develop backpropagation,
これから逆伝搬を開発します
which is precisely the reverse of feedforward.
これはまさにフィードフォワードの逆です
So, we are going to calculate the derivative of
連鎖法則を使って
this error function with respect to each of the weights in
ラベル内の各重みに対する
the labels by using the chain rule.
この誤差関数の微分係数を計算します
So, let us recall that our error function is this formula over here,
誤差関数がこの式であったことを思い出しましょう
which is a function of the prediction ŷ.
これは予測ŷの関数です
But, since the prediction is a function of all the weights wij,
ただし予測はすべての重みwijの関数であるため
then the error function can be seen as the function on all the wij.
誤差関数はwijすべてに対する関数と見なすことができます
Therefore, the gradient is simply the vector formed by
したがって勾配は単に
all the partial derivatives of the error function E with respect to each of the weights.
各重みに対する誤差関数Eのすべての偏微分係数で形成されるベクターです
So, let us calculate one of these derivatives.
これらの微分係数の1つを計算しましょう
Let us calculate derivative of E with respect to W11 superscript 1.
W11上付き1に対するEの微分係数を計算しましょう
So, since the prediction is simply a composition of functions and by the chain rule,
予測は単に関数の合成であり 連鎖法則によるものであるため
we know that the derivative with respect to this
これに対する微分係数は
is the product of all the partial derivatives.
すべての偏微分係数の積であることがわかります
In this case, the derivative E with respect
この例では W11に対する微分係数Eは
to W11 is the derivative of either respect to ŷ times
ŷに対する微分係数×hに対する微分係数ŷ
the derivative ŷ with respect to h
×h1に対する微分係数h
times the derivative h with respect to h1 times the derivative h1 with respect to W11.
×W11に対する微分係数h1で求めることができます
This may seem complicated,
複雑なように見えますが
but the fact that we can calculate a derivative of
実は4つの微分係数を乗算するだけで
such a complicated composition function by just
このような複雑な合成関数の微分係数を
multiplying 4 partial derivatives is remarkable.
計算できます
Now, we have already calculated the first one,
最初の微分係数
the derivative of E with respect to ŷ.
つまりŷに対する微分係数の計算が終わりました
And if you remember, we got ŷ minus y.
ŷマイナスyは以前求めましたね
So, let us calculate the other ones.
ほかの微分係数を計算しましょう
Let us zoom in a bit and look at just one piece of our multi-layer perceptron.
少しズームインして 多層パーセプトロンの一部を見てみましょう
The inputs are some values h1 and h2,
h1やh2などの入力は
which are values coming in from before.
それより前の計算から取得します
And once we apply the sigmoid and a linear function
バイアスユニットに対応するh1、h2、1に
on h1 and h2 and 1 corresponding to the biased unit,
シグモイドと線形関数を適用すると
we get a result h. So,
結果はhになります
now what is the derivative of h with respect to h1?
それでは h1に対するhの微分係数は何でしょうか?
Well, h is a sum of three things and only one of them contains h1.
hは3項の合計であり それらの1つだけにh1が含まれています
So, the second and the third summon just give us a derivative of 0.
第2項と第3項は微分係数がゼロになります
The first summon gives us W11 superscript 2 because that is a constant,
第1項では 定数であるW11上付き2と
and that times the derivative of the sigmoid function with respect to h1.
h1に対するシグモイド関数の微分係数を掛け合わせます
This is something that we calculated below in the instructor comments,
これは計算結果であり その内容は下記の「講師注記」欄にあります
which is that the sigmoid function has a beautiful derivative,
つまり シグモイド関数は美しい微分係数をとるということです
namely the derivative of sigmoid of h is
hのシグモイドの導関数は hのシグモイド×1-hのシグモイドで求められます
precisely sigmoid of h times 1 minus sigmoid of h. Again,
繰り返しますが
you can see this development underneath in the instructor comments.
計算内容は下記の「講師注記」欄で確認できます
You also have the chance to code this in the quiz because at the end of the day,
1日の締めくくりにクイズでこれをコーディングしてもらいます
we just code these formulas and then use them forever, and that is it.
これらの式をコーディングして 先々で使用します
That is how you train a neural network.
ニューラルネットワークのトレーニング方法は以上です